Lish mss., 1951-2017 LMC 2404
Lilly Library
Lish mss.
1951-2017
Lilly Library
Lish, Gordon.
LMC 2404
142 Boxes
The Lish mss., 1951-2017, consists of the correspondence, manuscripts, and papers of editor, writer, and teacher Gordon Lish, 1934-.
Access Restrictions
This collection is open for research.
Many collections are housed offsite; retrieval requires advance notice. Please make an appointment a minimum of one week in advance of your visit.
Acquisition Information
Acquired: 1991
Biographical Note
Gordon Lish, 1934-, is an American literary editor and writer. He was born and raised in Hewlett, New York, and graduated from the University of Arizona. He became founder and editor of the avant-garde literary magazine Genesis West, and went on to serve as editor for Esquire from 1969-1977 and Alfred A. Knopf from 1977-1995. Known as Captain Fiction, Lish mentored and championed several of the most prominent American authors of the second half of the 20th century, including Raymond Carver, Don DeLillo, Cynthia Ozick, Barry Hannah, Richard Ford, Amy Hempel, and T. Coraghessan Boyle. Lish is the author of Dear Mr. Capote, Peru, What I Know So Far, and other literary works. He is renowned for his writing seminars, held at many universities across the country as well as the Center for Fiction in New York City.
Scope and Content Note
Correspondence is divided into Individual, General, Additional, Personal, and Esquire. Writings are divided into Other Authors, Gordon Lish, and Additional. The Other Authors subseries includes original drafts and proofs from the works of Carver, DeLillo, and numerous other notable authors. Within Lish's own subseries are proofs of the publication The Quarterly. Photographs include pictures of Lish, Raymond Carver, James Dickey, and Neal Cassady. Legal records include court transcripts and filings of Lish v. Harper's (1992), and a book agreement between Raymond Carver and McGraw-Hill. Audio-Visual materials include a videotape of Lish's appearance on The Dick Cavett Show and audiotapes of students in Lish's writing classes. The Miscellaneous series includes materials from Lish's writing workshop, and a list of Lish's published writings (1956-1987).
Arrangement
The collection is organized into the following series: I. Correspondence; II. Writings; III. Newspaper Clippings; IV. Photographs; V. Artwork; VI. Legal; VII. Realia; VIII. Audio-Visual; IX. Miscellaneous; X. Additions
Related Materials
See Lish mss. II, also located at the Lilly Library, Indiana University, Bloomington, Indiana.
Authors, American--Correspondence; American literature--20th Century; Lish, Gordon.; Bass, Rick, 1958- --Correspondence.; Beattie, Ann --Correspondence.; Bellow, Saul --Correspondence.; Bloom, Harold --Correspondence.; Bowles, Paul, 1910-1999 --Correspondence.; Boyle, T. Coraghessan --Correspondence.; Brodkey, Harold --Correspondence.; Buckley, William F. (William Frank), 1925-2008 --Correspondence.; Carver, Raymond, 1938-1988 --Correspondence.; Cheever, John --Correspondence.; Dickey, James --Correspondence.; Heller, Joseph --Correspondence.; Hemingway, Mary Elizabeth, 1905- --Correspondence.; Irving, John, 1942- --Correspondence.; Kesey, Ken --Correspondence.; Kubrick, Stanley --Correspondence.; Mailer, Norman --Correspondence.; Miller, Arthur, 1915-2005 --Correspondence.; Miller, Henry, 1891-1980 --Correspondence.; Nabokova, Vera --Correspondence.; Nixon, Richard M. (Richard Milhous), 1913-1994 --Correspondence.; Oates, Joyce Carol, 1938- --Correspondence.; Ozick, Cynthia --Correspondence.; Roth, Philip --Correspondence.; Theroux, Peter --Correspondence.; Warren, Robert Penn, 1905-1989 --Correspondence.; Wolfe, Tom --Correspondence.; Sontag, Susan, 1933-2004 --Correspondence.
- I. Correspondence
  - Individual
    - Adams - Bellow (Box 1)
      - Adams, Alice, 1971 (Box 1)
      - Adams, Ralph, 1996-1997 (Box 1)
      - Allen, Abigail, 1996 (Box 1)
      - Allen, Barton, 1992-1997 (Box 1)
      - Angell, Roger, 1972-1978 (Box 1)
      - Apple, Max, 1973-1979 (Box 1)
      - Auster, Paul, 1985-1989 (Box 1)
      - Baird, Ansie, 1977-2010; (8 folders) (Box 1)
      - Barth, John, 1972-1984 (Box 1)
      - Bass, Rick, 1975-1995; (11 folders) (Box 1)
      - Bausch, Richard, 1976-1985; (2 folders) (Box 1)
      - Baxter, Charles, 1978-1983 (Box 1)
      - Beattie, Ann, 1971-1991 (Box 1)
      - Belden, Kathryn, 1996-1997 (Box 1)
      - Bellow, Saul, 1970-1971 (Box 1)
    - Berne - Carver (start) (Box 2)
      - Berne, Carol, 1969-1985 (Box 2)
      - Berkman, Johanna, 1997 (Box 2)
      - Berne, Betsy, 1996 (Box 2)
      - Bloom, Harold, 1975-1988 (Box 2)
      - Blount, Jr., Roy, 1978-1987 (Box 2)
      - Britton, Burt, 1980-1989 (Box 2)
      - Borus, Victoria, 1996; (2 folders) (Box 2)
      - Bowles, Paul, 1970-1975 (Box 2)
      - Boyle, Kay, 1966-1975 (Box 2)
      - Boyle, T. Coraghessan, 1974-1991 (Box 2)
      - Brodkey, Harold, 1975-1988 (Box 2)
      - Broyard, Anatole, 1968-1983 (Box 2)
      - Buckley, William F., 1975-1987 (Box 2)
      - Bumpus, Jerry, 1969-1988 (Box 2)
      - Burgess, Anthony, 1975 (Box 2)
      - Burke, Kenneth, 1979-1985 (Box 2)
      - Burton, Jane, 1999-2000; 2005; (3 folders) (Box 2)
      - Busch, Frederick, 1970-1987; (3 folders) (Box 2)
      - Carruth, Hayden, 1965-2001 (Box 2)
      - Carson, Anne, 1987-1993 (Box 2)
      - Carson, L.M. Kit, 1974 (Box 2)
      - Carter, Rubin "Hurricane", 1973 (Box 2)
      - Carver, Raymond, 1969-1975; (3 folders) (Box 2)
    - Carver (end) - DeLillo (Box 3)
      - Carver, Raymond, 1976-1983; undated; (7 folders) (Box 3)
      - Casalini, Mario, 1996 (Box 3)
      - Cassady, Carolyn, 1968-1990 (Box 3)
      - Cerf, Emily, 1993-1997 (Box 3)
      - Charyn, Jerome, 1974-1983 (Box 3)
      - Cheever, John, 1969-1980 (Box 3)
      - Clark, Eleanor, 1970-1977 (Box 3)
      - Coe, Christopher, 1984-1988; (3 folders) (Box 3)
      - Cone, Jon, 1996-1997 (Box 3)
      - Connell, Evan, 1970-1978 (Box 3)
      - Connole, Patrick, 1997 (Box 3)
      - Conrad, Barnaby, 1974-1979 (Box 3)
      - Crawford, Stanley, 1972-1984; 1988 (Box 3)
      - Crean, Patrick, 1996 (Box 3)
      - Danatt, Adrian, 1997 (Box 3)
      - Davis, Jodi, 1997-2001; (2 folders) (Box 3)
      - DeLillo, Don, 1972-1995; (6 folders) (Box 3)
    - DeLillo (end) - Erian (Box 4)
      - DeLillo, Don, 1996-2012; undated; (5 folders) (Box 4)
      - DeMarinis, Rick, 1971-1988 (Box 4)
      - DesPres, Terrence, 1975-1987; (3 folders) (Box 4)
      - Dickey, James, 1970-1996; (11 folders) (Box 4)
      - Didion, Joan, 1973 (Box 4)
      - di Giovanni, Norman Thomas, 1970-1978 (Box 4)
      - Doctorow, E.L., 1974-1985 (Box 4)
      - Donoghue, Denis, 1977-1998; undated; (7 folders) (Box 4)
      - Eastlake, William, 1969-1972 (Box 4)
      - Edson, Russell, 1969-1978; 2004 (Box 4)
      - Ehlen, Patrick, 1998-2000 (Box 4)
      - Elkin, Stanley, 1966-1980 (Box 4)
      - Ellenberg, Jordan, 1996 (Box 4)
      - Ellison, Harlan, 1976 (Box 4)
      - Ellmann, Richard, 1976-1977 (Box 4)
      - Eno, Will, 1992-2011; (7 folders) (Box 4)
      - Epstein, Leslie, 1977-1982 (Box 4)
      - Erian, Alicia, 1997 (Box 4)
    - Evenson - Geeslin (Box 5)
      - Evenson, Brian, 1991-2008; (6 folders) (Box 5)
      - Exley, Fred, 1973-1986 (Box 5)
      - Fiedler, Leslie, 1970-1988; (2 folders) (Box 5)
      - Ford, Richard, 1976-1985 (Box 5)
      - Fraser, Kathleen, 1977-1979 (Box 5)
      - Freed, Lynn, 1996-1997 (Box 5)
      - Friedman, Bruce Jay, 1968-2012 (Box 5)
      - Garcia Marquez, Gabriel, undated (Box 5)
      - Gangemi, Ken, 1969-1985 (Box 5)
      - Gardner, John, 1970-1978 (Box 5)
      - Garrett, George, 1966-1972; (2 folders) (Box 5)
      - Gass, William, 1966-1981 (Box 5)
      - Geeslin, Campbell, 1989-1994; (9 folders) (Box 5)
    - Geeslin (end) - Gold (Box 6)
      - Geeslin, Campbell, 1996-2012; (16 folders) (Box 6)
      - Gekiere, Madeleine, 1997 (Box 6)
      - Gilbert, Jack, 1975-1997; 2004; (5 folders) (Box 6)
      - Gilman, Richard, 1973-1979 (Box 6)
      - Gingrich, Arnold and Jane, 1971-1975 (Box 6)
      - Girodias, Maurice, 1970-1976 (Box 6)
      - Godwin, Gail, 1971-1977 (Box 6)
      - Gold, Herbert, 1968-1979; undated; (4 folders) (Box 6)
    - Gori-Montanelli - Hemingway (Box 7)
      - Gori-Montanelli, Margery, 1989-2011; (8 folders) (Box 7)
      - Gottlieb, Robert, 1971-1986; (2 folders) (Box 7)
      - Gottlieb, Theodore, 1976-1983 (Box 7)
      - Graves, John, 1968-1977; 1991 (Box 7)
      - Greenberg, Pamela, 1996 (Box 7)
      - Guerard, Albert J., 1971-1978 (Box 7)
      - Guglielmina, Pierre, 1993-2000 (Box 7)
      - Halberstadt, John, undated (Box 7)
      - Hannah, Barry, 1974-2008; (13 folders) (Box 7)
      - Harrison, Beth, 1996 (Box 7)
      - Harrison, William, 1970-1990; (4 folders) (Box 7)
      - Hawkes, John, 1966-1973; 1984 (Box 7)
      - Heller, Joseph, 1976-1978 (Box 7)
      - Hemingway, Mary, 1970-1978 (Box 7)
    - Hempel (Box 8)
      - Hempel, Amy, 1980-2001; (19 folders) (Box 8)
    - Hempel (end) - Janowitz (Box 9)
      - Hempel, Amy, 2002-2009; (11 folders) (Box 9)
      - Herman, Victor, 1977-1979 (Box 9)
      - Herr, Michael, 1976 (Box 9)
      - Hill, Carol, 1975-1982 (Box 9)
      - Hochman, Sandra, 1975 (Box 9)
      - Hogan, Wayne, 1992-2011; (4 folders) (Box 9)
      - Holland, Noy [with Sam Michel], 1985-2011; (5 folders) (Box 9)
      - Irving, John, 1972-1978; 1984; (3 folders) (Box 9)
      - Janowitz, Phyllis, 1974-1986; (2 folders) (Box 9)
    - Jiles - Kimball (Box 10)
      - Jiles, Paulette, 1986-2012; (14 folders) (Box 10)
      - Joyce, William, 1973-1983 (Box 10)
      - Kagan, Wendy, 1996 (Box 10)
      - Kauffman, Janet, 1980-1990 (Box 10)
      - Kazin, Alfred, 1971-1986 (Box 10)
      - Keach, Stacy, 1969-1973 (Box 10)
      - Keillor, Garrison, 1984 (Box 10)
      - Kennedy, Raymond, 1972-1990; (2 folders) (Box 10)
      - Kesey, Ken, 1968-1980 (Box 10)
      - Kessler, Jascha, 1971-1979 (Box 10)
      - Kimball, Michael, 1991-2000 (Box 10)
    - Kirkpatrick - Lock (Box 11)
      - Kirkpatrick, Bear, 1992-2007; (5 folders) (Box 11)
      - Kirn, Walter, 1988-1992 (Box 11)
      - Kline, Kevin, 2001 (Box 11)
      - Koperwas, Sam, 1973-1983 (Box 11)
      - Kosinski, Jerzy, 1974 (Box 11)
      - Kotzwinkle, William, 1970-1978; 1996-1997; (2 folders) (Box 11)
      - Kracayna, Anna, 1996-1997; (3 folders) (Box 11)
      - Krupp, Carolyn, 1995-2004 (Box 11)
      - Kubrick, Stanley, 1976-1982 (Box 11)
      - Lane, Simon, 1994-2001; (2 folders) (Box 11)
      - Laughlin, James, 1966-1988; (6 folders) (Box 11)
      - Lee, Harper, 1984 (Box 11)
      - Le Guin, Ursula K., 1977 (Box 11)
      - Lehmann-Haupt, Alexander, 1972-1991 (Box 11)
      - L'Heureux, John, 1971-1989 (Box 11)
      - Lish, Peter, 1987-1998 (Box 11)
      - Lock, Norman, 1996; 2000-2001; (3 folders) (Box 11)
    - Lock (cont.) (Box 12)
      - Lock, Norman, 2001-2006; (21 folders) (Box 12)
    - Lock (end) - Malin (Box 13)
      - Lock, Norman, 2007-2008; (5 folders) (Box 13)
      - Loomis, Ed, 1966-1991 (Box 13)
      - Lurie, Morris, 1971-1989; (8 folders) (Box 13)
      - Lutz, Gary, 1992-2011; (6 folders) (Box 13)
      - McCall, Bruce, 1975-1986; (3 folders) (Box 13)
      - McCarthy, Mary, 1971-1972 (Box 13)
      - McEwan, Ian, 1973-1977 (Box 13)
      - McGuane, Tom, 1975-1984 (Box 13)
      - McInerney, Jay, 1985 (Box 13)
      - McMurtry, Larry, 1968 (Box 13)
      - Mailer, Norman, 1966-1992 (Box 13)
      - Malamud, Bernard, 1969-1980 (Box 13)
      - Malick, Terrence, 1971-1974 (Box 13)
      - Malin, Irving, 1966-1983; (4 folders) (Box 13)
    - Malin (end) - Meissner (Box 14)
      - Malin, Irving, 1984-2005; undated; (9 folders) (Box 14)
      - Malkovich, John, 1999 (Box 14)
      - Malone, Michael, 1974-1982; (2 folders) (Box 14)
      - Markus, Peter, 1996-2007; (2 folders) (Box 14)
      - Marten, Eugene, 2000-2001 (Box 14)
      - Martone, Michael, 1979-1987; (2 folders) (Box 14)
      - Marx, Paty, 1992-1998 (Box 14)
        - Topical melatonin spray, 2015 (Box 14)
      - Massik, Carolyn, 1996-2009; (6 folders) (Box 14)
      - Meissner, Jan, 1992-1996 (Box 14)
    - Michaels - Ozick (Box 15)
      - Michaels, Leonard, 1970-1985 (Box 15)
      - Michel, Sam, 1989-2001 (Box 15)
      - Midwood, Bart, 1971-1980 (Box 15)
      - Milch, David, 1975-1984 (Box 15)
      - Miller, Arthur, 1971-1977; 1984 (Box 15)
      - Miller, Henry, 1970-1971 (Box 15)
      - Morris, Wright, 1969-1983 (Box 15)
      - Nabakov, Vera, (for Vladimir), 1970-1977 (Box 15)
      - Nemerov, Howard, 1969-1985 (Box 15)
      - Newman, Charles, 1970-1974 (Box 15)
      - Nixon, Richard, 1968-1969 (Box 15)
      - Oakes, John, 1996-1997 (Box 15)
      - Oates, Joyce Carol, 1969-1990 (Box 15)
      - O'Connor, Flannery, 1962 (Box 15)
      - Olsen, Tillie, 1968-1971 (Box 15)
      - Ostroff, Anthony, 1972-1977 (Box 15)
      - Ozick, Cynthia, 1970-1988; (18 folders) (Box 15)
    - Ozick (end) - Renner (Box 16)
      - Ozick, Cynthia, 1989-2011; (16 folders) (Box 16)
      - Paglia, Camille, 1990-1991 (Box 16)
      - Panurgias, Basile, 1997 (Box 16)
      - Percy, Walker, 1972-1984 (Box 16)
      - Persson, Russell, 1995-2002 (Box 16)
      - Pinson, David, 1993-2009; (2 folders) (Box 16)
      - Portis, Charles, 1994 (Box 16)
      - Purdy, James, 1968-1989; (6 folders) (Box 16)
      - Rabassa, Gregory, 1972-1976 (Box 16)
      - Raffel, Dawn, 1992-2008 (Box 16)
      - Redel, Victoria, 1992-2000 (Box 16)
      - Renner, Cooper, 1988-1998; (5 folders) (Box 16)
    - Renner (end) - Roth (Box 17)
      - Renner, Cooper, 1999-2011; (13 folders) (Box 17)
      - Riley, Jill Ellyn, 1996-1997 (Box 17)
      - Robbins, Tom, 1970-1976 (Box 17)
      - Roberts, Daniel, 1996 (Box 17)
      - Robison, Mary, 1977-1995; (2 folders) (Box 17)
      - Rosenberg, David, 1999-2000 (Box 17)
      - Rosenwald, Nina, 1992-2000; (3 folders) (Box 17)
      - Ross, Helen, 1998-2010 (Box 17)
      - Roth, Philip, 1970-1984 (Box 17)
    - Rybicki - Sayer (Box 18)
      - Rybicki, John, 1989-2009; (17 folders) (Box 18)
      - Ryder, Pamela, 1992-2010 (Box 18)
      - Sarki, Michael, 1995-2012; (6 folders) (Box 18)
      - Sayer, Allison, 1996-1997 (Box 18)
      - Sayer, Katherine, 1996-1997 (Box 18)
    - Selzer - Williams (Box 19)
      - Selzer, Richard, 1971-1985; (4 folders) (Box 19)
      - Shawn, Wallace, 1978 (Box 19)
      - Shawn, William, 1984-1985 (Box 19)
      - Shawver, James, 1989 (Box 19)
      - Sontag, Susan, 1975-1978 (Box 19)
      - Sorrentino, Gilbert, 1972-1996 (Box 19)
      - Styron, William, 1972 (Box 19)
      - Tanner, Tony, 1972-1979 (Box 19)
      - Taylor, Nelson, 1996 (Box 19)
      - Theroux, Alexander, 1972-1989; (6 folders) (Box 19)
      - Theroux, Paul, 1969-1976 (Box 19)
      - Theroux, Peter, 1976-1978 (Box 19)
      - Thompson, Hunter S., 1975-1978 (Box 19)
      - Tolkin, Michael, 1974 (Box 19)
      - Trucks, Rob, 1996-1997 (Box 19)
      - Tyler, Anne, 1985-1986 (Box 19)
      - Tynan, Kenneth, 1977 (Box 19)
      - Updike, John, 1971-1988 (Box 19)
      - Walker, John, 1972-1988; (3 folders) (Box 19)
      - Wallace, David Foster, 1987 (Box 19)
      - Warren, Robert Penn, 1971-1978 (Box 19)
      - Welty, Eudora, 1975 (Box 19)
      - Williams, Diane, 1985-1991; (10 folders) (Box 19)
    - Williams (end) - Ziglar (Box 20)
      - Williams, Diane, 1992-1999; (6 folders) (Box 20)
      - Williams, Tennessee, 1977 (Box 20)
      - Wilson, Edmund, 1971 (Box 20)
      - Wolcott, James, 1985-1987 (Box 20)
      - Wolf, Don, 1993-2001; (2 folders) (Box 20)
      - Wolfe, Tom, 1973-1983; (3 folders) (Box 20)
      - Wolff, Tobias, 1980-1985 (Box 20)
      - Wolitzer, Hilma, 1969-1979 (Box 20)
      - Ziglar, Vincent, 1995-2000 (Box 20)
  - General
    - 1959 - 1970, Aug. (Box 21)
    - 1970, Sept. - 1972, Sept. (Box 22)
    - 1972 Oct. - 1974, Jul. (Box 23)
    - 1974 Aug. - 1975, 15 Dec. (Box 24)
      Scope and Contents
      Includes correspondence between Lish and Frank Stanford
    - 1975, 16 Dec. - 1977, 20 Mar. (Box 25)
    - 1977, 21 Mar. - 1978 Feb. (Box 26)
    - 1978, Mar. - 1979 May (Box 27)
    - 1979, Jun. - 1980 Nov. (Box 28)
    - 1980, Dec. - 1982, Mar. (Box 29)
    - 1982, Apr. - 1983, Sept. (Box 30)
    - 1983, Oct. - 1984, Nov. (Box 31)
    - 1984, Dec. - 1985 (Box 32)
    - 1986 (Box 33)
    - 1987 (Box 34)
    - 1988 (Box 35)
    - 1989 (Box 36)
    - 1990 (Box 37)
    - 1991, Jan. - Sept. (Box 38)
    - 1991, Oct. - 1992, Jun. (Box 87)
    - 1992, Jul. - 1993, Feb. (Box 88)
    - 1993, Mar. - Dec. (Box 89)
    - 1994 (Box 90)
    - 1994, undated (Box 91)
    - 1995, Nov. - 1997, Oct. (Box 92)
    - 1997, Nov. - 1999 (Box 93)
    - 2000-2003 (Box 94)
    - 2004-2006 (Box 95)
    - 2007 - 2009, Apr. (Box 96)
    - 2009, May - 2010, Oct. (Box 97)
    - 2010, Nov. - 2012, Feb. (Box 98)
  - Additional
    (includes both individual and general correspondence)
    - Hintze, Erich (Box 110)
    - Kohler, Sheila (Box 110)
    - Lemann, Nancy (Box 110)
    - Lifschey, Paula (Box 110)
    - 1990s (Box 110)
    - 2000s (Box 110)
    - Unidentified (Box 110)
    - 1960s (Box 119)
    - 1971-1973 (Box 119)
    - 1974-1977 (Box 119)
    - 1978-1979 (Box 119)
    - 1980-1989 (Box 119)
    - 1990-1992 (Box 119)
    - 1992-1993 (Box 119)
    - 1994-1995 (Box 119)
    - 1996-1999 (Box 119)
    - 2000-2001 (Box 119)
    - 2002-2003 (Box 119)
    - 2004 (Box 119)
    - 2005-2010 (Box 119)
    - Undated, (3 folders) (Box 119)
  - Personal
    - 1971 (Box 119)
    - 1972 (Box 119)
    - 1973 (Box 119)
    - 1974 (Box 119)
    - 1975 (Box 119)
    - 1976 (Box 119)
    - 1977 (Box 119)
    - 1978 (Box 119)
    - 1979 (Box 119)
    - 1980s (Box 119)
    - 1990s (Box 119)
    - 2000s (Box 119)
    - Undated, (2 folders) (Box 119)
    - Gutbrod, Jess, 2007 (Box 120)
    - Gutbrod, Jess, 2008, Jan. (Box 120)
    - Gutbrod, Jess, 2008, Feb. (Box 120)
    - Gutbrod, Jess, 2008, Mar. (Box 120)
    - Gutbrod, Jess, 2008, Apr. - May; undated (Box 120)
    - Gutbrod, Jess, undated; (3 folders) (Box 120)
    - Kenan, Shomzian, 2008-2009 (Box 120)
    - 1969 (Box 120)
    - 1975-1999 (Box 120)
    - 1996 (Box 120)
    - 1997, Feb. (Box 120)
    - 1997, Mar. (Box 120)
    - 1997, Apr. (Box 120)
    - 1997, May (Box 120)
    - 2000-2002 (Box 120)
    - 2003 (Box 120)
    - 2004-2009 (Box 120)
    - Undated, (2 folders) (Box 120)
  - Esquire
    - Gordon Lish memos (Box 111)
    - Henderson, Bill, 1970s (Box 111)
    - A-C, undated (Box 111)
    - D, undated (Box 111)
    - D-F, undated (Box 111)
    - G-H, undated (Box 111)
    - G-H, undated (Box 111)
    - J-K, undated (Box 111)
    - L-M, undated (Box 111)
    - N-R, undated (Box 111)
    - S-T, undated (Box 111)
    - U-Z, undated (Box 111)
    - 1st name only, A-H (Box 111)
    - 1st name only, I-L (Box 111)
    - 1st name only, M-Z (Box 111)
    - Undated, (2 folders) (Box 111)
    - Unidentified, undated; (2 folders) (Box 111)
    - 1969-1970 (Box 112)
    - 1970, (2 folders) (Box 112)
    - 1971, (2 folders) (Box 112)
    - 1972, (3 folders) (Box 112)
    - ca. 1972 (Box 112)
    - 1972-1973 (Box 112)
    - 1973, (3 folders) (Box 112)
    - 1973-1974 (Box 112)
    - 1974, Jan. - Jun. (Box 112)
    - 1974, Jul. - Dec. (Box 112)
    - 1974, Jan. - 1975 Jan. (Box 112)
    - 1975 (Box 112)
    - ca. 1975 (Box 112)
    - 1976, Jan. - May (Box 112)
    - 1976, Jun. - Dec. (Box 112)
    - 1976 (Box 112)
    - 1977 (Box 112)
    - Undated (Box 112)
- II. Writings
  - By Other Authors
    General
    Note: some authors continued in the Additional Writings subseries.
    - Abrahams - Baumgarten (Box 39)
      - Abrahams, Bill (Box 39)
        - Fifty Years of the American Short Story... Introduction (Box 39)
      - Adams, Ralph (Box 39)
        - Even a Wild Pitch Beans the Soul as the Bad Swing Muggeth the Heart (Box 39)
        - Notes Toward an Elegy (Box 39)
      - Adams, Stanford (Box 39)
        - Appendix (Box 39)
      - Ahn, Michael (Box 39)
        - Jennifer [aka Here Kitty] (Box 39)
        - Cruise [A Reminder] (Box 39)
      - Aldrich, Marcia (Box 39)
        - Yes (Box 39)
      - Alexander, Edward (Box 39)
        - Edward Alexander to Q [aka The Last Refuge of a Scoundrel] (Box 39)
      - Allen, Abigail (Box 39)
        - Tahiti (Box 39)
        - The Trip [aka Oklahoma, 1995 ] (Box 39)
        - The President (Box 39)
        - The Color Gold You're Supposed to Get [aka Prince] (Box 39)
        - School [aka The String Orchestra] (Box 39)
        - The Stylist (Box 39)
        - The Wheelers (Box 39)
      - Allen, Barton (Box 39)
        - Among the Coven (Box 39)
        - The Androgynous Superhero (Box 39)
        - The Angle (Box 39)
        - Bliss (Box 39)
        - Circle the Letters of Your Name (Box 39)
        - The Cork-stripper's Son (Box 39)
        - Dancing (Box 39)
        - Everything for Form (Box 39)
        - Exciting Preview (Box 39)
        - Glued Construction (Box 39)
        - God's God (Box 39)
        - The Jumping Rope (Box 39)
        - The Letter Under the Pillow (Box 39)
        - Memory (Box 39)
        - My Immolations (Box 39)
        - Nosegay (Box 39)
        - The Paralysis (Box 39)
        - Pub (Box 39)
        - A Question While Driving (Box 39)
        - Romancing No One (Box 39)
        - Scabs (Box 39)
        - The Scale (Box 39)
        - Sleep in My Glass Eye (Box 39)
        - The Transplant (Box 39)
        - Voir Dire (Box 39)
        - Why Nightcrawlers Crawl (Box 39)
        - Poet Student Barton Allen Gives Reading in New York [Lake Forest College Stentor, ], 28 April 1993 (Box 39)
        - [Unnamed Collection], 1993 (Box 39)
          - The First (Box 39)
          - The Boldest Confession I Will Ever Make (Box 39)
          - Terra Cotta (Box 39)
          - The Covenant (Box 39)
          - The Thirst (Box 39)
          - My Immolations (Box 39)
          - The Cradle (Box 39)
          - Mammals (Box 39)
          - The Mermaids, Adultery, the Curing of the Bait (Box 39)
          - Shajida, Mermaid in the Tides of Ennfe (Box 39)
          - My Father's Lover's Tomatoes (Box 39)
          - The Imposter (Box 39)
          - Adam's Boast (Box 39)
          - Adam Renaming (Box 39)
          - Intaglio, My Mother's Clothes (Box 39)
          - Samsa, Dying in his Berth (Box 39)
          - The Drive (Box 39)
          - Wax Numen (Box 39)
          - Beyond the Plaster Cast (Box 39)
          - Entre Chien et Loup (Box 39)
          - An Hour After the Bath (Box 39)
          - The Statues (Box 39)
          - The Pasteboard Tube (Box 39)
          - Dancing (Box 39)
          - First-Song (Box 39)
          - In Darkness I Tell You This (Box 39)
          - Origin (Box 39)
          - The Cork-Stripper's Son (Box 39)
          - Bright Crossing (Box 39)
          - Epilogue (Box 39)
          - God's God (Box 39)
          - Wet Rocks (Box 39)
          - The Infant's Songs [aka The Infant's Curse] (Box 39)
          - The Infant's Song (Box 39)
          - Here Is My Jump Rope Burning (Box 39)
          - Though the Goat will Dance and the Hive Be Full (Box 39)
          - Romancing No One (Box 39)
          - The Tag (Box 39)
          - Aging in My Palace Well (Box 39)
          - The Beast (Box 39)
          - People (Box 39)
          - Charles the Zoologist (Box 39)
          - Three Line Poem (Box 39)
          - The Stepson's Song (Box 39)
          - Do You See the Fear? (Box 39)
          - Wet Dream (Box 39)
          - Plankton (Box 39)
      - Allen, Jennifer, (5 folders) (Box 39)
        - Stories, (1 folder) (Box 39)
          - 1987 (Box 39)
          - Better Get Your Angel On (Box 39)
          - Dinner (Box 39)
          - Hello? Merry Christmas? Hello? (Box 39)
          - Let Me Have You (Box 39)
          - Mom and Pop (Box 39)
          - Tricentennial (Box 39)